CMCT发布
未来
The future
南北极冰水彻底融化
The polar ice caps have melted
地球被淹没在海洋中
covering the Earth with water
幸存者逐渐建立一个新世界
Those who survived have adapted...
"水世界"
to a new world.
我没上你船[印地语]
我不会干那种事的
你下去了很长时间
我的船出了点问题
破了一个大洞 幸好还有地方让我呼吸
够倒霉的 说英语吧
Bad luck, English.
最近那些贩奴商生产出了一种效果很好的氧化剂
But the Slavers are producing a good grade of poxy these days.
跟你换一把泥土 或是那个风铃
Cost you a handful of dirt... or maybe that wind chime.
- 你来这里干嘛? - 等你呗
- What are you doin' here? - Just waiting.
你的臭手别碰船帆
Take your hand off the sail.
手拿开
Take it off!
我之前见过你的船 却没见过你
I've seen your boat before. Haven't seen you.
是合法的先占
Took it legal.
我发现这船的时候船主已经死了
Previous owner was dead on the tiller when I found it.
我高价转卖之前你还有一个小时的时间考虑
You had another hour before I traded up again.
赚得更多是我的宗旨
Just improving my means.
- 好吧 算我欠你个人情 - 谢啦 不用了
- Well, I owe you then. - No, thanks.
我的装备已经补足了 我才从一个环礁基地出来
I got all the supplies I need. Just came from an atoll.
你想去的话 向东航行八天
Eight days east, if you're interested.
- 海行者碰面通常都要交换 - 我知道规矩
- Two drifters meet, something needs to be exchanged. - I know the code.
但是这次我就免费给你
But I'll give you this one for free.
在这片汪洋中绝不会有免费午餐的
Nothing's free in Waterworld.
是啊
Ha-ha. Yeah.
是掠海者
Smokers.
风势正好助我顺利开溜
Just enough wind to get away clean.
就别管那包东西了
Forget the bag.
那不值得你一搏 更何况你连帆都没拉起来
It's not worth it. You'll never make it with your sails down.
Hey!
祝你好运啦
What can I say?
- 乔 他要开溜 - 搞什么鬼?
- Joe, he's goin' for it. - What the hell?
真是大开眼界啊
Never seen that before.
快启动 快啊 快踩油门
Here we go! Go! Drive! Drive!
快点 再快点
Faster! Faster! Whoo!
快点 要被他抢走了
Come on! He's gonna get it! He's gonna get it!
- 快逮他 - 上呀! 上呀!
- Pick her up! - Get it! Get it!
不 别
Oh, no!
有船接近 到门外了
Inbound! Straight out from the gates.
你讲什么话?
英文
English.
已经收市了 海行者 今天已经不再交易了
Flag's down, drifter. We got enough traders.
他拿的是什么?
泥土
Dirt.
开门
Open the gates!
化骨为浆
Bones to berries.
抽脉为藤
Veins to vine.
肢骨化为大树 血浆变盐水
These tendons to trees. This blood to brine.
岁月夺走了她的生命
Too old she was.
但她却恩泽予我们
This woman does leave us
我们在上帝面前收下她的恩泽并铭记她
ecycled and enshrined in the presence of Him who leads us.
那是什么?
What is that?
你认识我吗?
You know me?
我知道你是谁
I know what you are.
很好 那你自然知道在这儿闹事
Good. Then you know if you look for trouble while you're here,
只会让你吃不完兜着走
you'll find more than you can handle.
我给你两个小时
You got two hours.
我只需要一小时
I'll only need one.
他走过来了
He's comin' over here.
- 给我 - 赏你们一人一个
- Me. - You each get one...
只要能在我回来前帮我看好船
if everything's here when I get back.
纯泥土
Pure dirt.
3.2公斤
3.2 kilos.
你从哪儿找来这么多泥土?
How'd you come by so much of it?
从这儿向西差不多30个海平线远的另一个环礁基地那儿
Another atoll 30 horizons west of here.
那他们是在哪儿弄到的呢
Where'd they get it?
- 他们没有透露 - 听说那地方的人
- They didn't say. - We heard about that place...
全都被杀光了
that they was all killed.
- 那就是他们不透露的原因 - 掠海者干的?
- That's why they didn't say. - Smokers?
也许是掠海者 也有可能是贩奴商
Maybe Smokers, maybe Slavers.
怎么样?要交易吗?
So what's the word? We tradin' or not?
我们就把它当成是 纯净水的价值交易
We'll tally it like, uh, pure hydro.
给你62块钱
Works out to... 62 chits.
我要加倍
I want twice that.
- 我只想喝一点水罢了 - 不行 除非你告诉我
- I just want one sip of hydro! - No, not 'til you tell me.
她背上有图案 我看过
She got inkings on her back. I seen her.
传说只要你能解开那孩子身上图案之谜
They say if you read the marks on the child,
那就能指引你到达陆地
they'll lead ya all the way to Dryland.
- 陆地只是神话 - 但还是有人相信
- Dryland's a myth. - Some still believe.
他们还说掠海者在找这小女孩
They say the Smokers even got an eye out for her.
是吗 那么 我们最好还是保密
Well, then, we'd better keep it to ourselves.
挺壮嘛
- 需要帮忙吗 - 是的
- Help you? - Yeah.
- 商店在哪里? - 就你眼前
- Where's the store? - You found it.
东西不多
You don't have much.
你就是带着泥土的那个人?
You the man with the dirt?
干杯
Skoal.
- 再来一杯 - 来两杯
- One more. - Make it two.
一个这么有钱的人会请陆上的朋友喝一杯的 我确定
A man this rich will buy for a fellow outwater, I'm sure.
就一杯
One.
你脚上这双鞋挺有趣的
That's an interesting pair of boots you got.
- 想交换吗? - 不想
- Trade? - No.
真可惜
Shame.
就是她
That's her
埃诺拉 你在干嘛?
Enola. Hey, what are you doing?
不行 你不能这样
No, you can't do that.
我还需要一块儿
I need another piece.
我想多画点
I want to draw some more.
我会拿给你的 去后面呆着去
I'll get it to you. Just stay in the back.
用这笔钱 你能好好冲个澡
With all those chits, you could order up a bath.
你用淡水洗过澡吗?
Have you ever had a freshwater bath?
你为什么找我说话?
Why are you talkin' to me?
我只想交个朋友
Just being friendly.
- 那是蕃茄树吗? - 对
- Is that a tomato plant? - Yeah.
你很有眼光啊
You have a keen eye.
曾经在图片上见过 怎么卖的?
Saw one in a picture. How much?
你一半的钱
Half your chits.
- 那些我也要 - 还要什么?
- I'll take them too. - Take what?
- 东西全被你买了 - 那些架子我也要
- You bought everything. - I'll take them shelves.
你在海上那15个月里都见到过什么
So, what did you see out there in your 15 months?
- 比如呢? - 这片水域的尽头
- Such as? - An end to all this water.
你问错人了
Askin' the wrong person.
他们今天不是埋葬了一个人吗?
The one they buried today?
她就是这儿的唯一尽头
She found the only end there is.
航海人 我给你一个建议
I've got a proposition for you, Mariner.
我不会留下来
I'm not staying.
我们没要你留下来
We're not asking you to.
我们要的是你的后裔
All we want is your seed.
找自己人虽然也行
We can look to our own for impregnation,
但是长此以往必会导致孩子的基因不良
but too much of that sort of thing gets... undesirable.
只要她怀了孕
When she's pregnant
你就可以带上你所需的所有补给继续你的行程
you go on your way with all the supplies you need.
别费神了 你们已经无药可救了
You don't have anything. You're dying.
没有人会在漂泊那么久之后竟对女人无动于衷的
No man stays out that long and turns down a woman.
- 他一定在隐瞒什么 - 说不定他是个掠海者间谍
- He's hiding something. - Maybe he's a Smoker spy.
只有长老让你走 你才能走
When the elders say so, you can leave,
否则别想走
and not before.
有鳃
Gills.
- 变种人 - 他是变种人
- Mutation! - He's a mutant!
我的手
My hand!
快撒网
Throw the nets!
你凭什么?
By what right...
凭你雇我来维持这里的秩序
You pay me to keep the peace.
绝不是这样的秩序
This isn't it.
- 他已经杀了我们一个人了 - 他只是自卫
- He has killed one of ours. - He was defending himself.
他必须被处决
He needs to be destroyed!
宰了他 我们得宰了他
Kill him. Let's kill him.
也许吧
That may be,
但绝不是在这儿更不是用这种方式
but not here and not like this.
那是什么?
What is it?
该死的
Damn.
他们看得太紧了 我没机会下手
It's tied. I can't get it off.
开门
Open the gate.
那是地图吗?
Is it a map?
如果你知道就告诉我 好吗 埃诺拉?
You'd tell me if you knew, wouldn't you, Enola?
- 你在画什么? - 我不知道
- What are you drawing? - I don't know.
海伦 你看 看这小天才的最新幻想
Helen, look. Look at the prodigal child's latest vision.
我们什么时候才能走?
How soon before we can leave?
我还不知道几时能走?
I don't have any idea yet where we can go.
我搞不懂她的刺青
I haven't figured out the tattoo on her back.
我真是个蠢蛋 答案看似近在眼前
I'm a stupid man. The answer's right there.
实则远在天边
It's just beyond me.
也许他知道
Maybe he knows.
是的我看到了那是蹼
Oh, yes, I see. They are webbed.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
8 9 有10个趾头 真不可思议
eight, nine, ten digits. That's wonderful.
他们说你有鳃
They tell me, too, that you have gills.
排列整齐的鳃 是已经退化还是真的有用?
Isotropic gills. Are they merely vestigial or are they functional now?
我叫葛雷格 我是说过来给你点
My name is Gregor. I've just come to pay you a little vi... vi...
老天啊
Oh, my God.
抱歉 我不是笑你
I'm sorry. I'm not laughing at you.
只是有点兴奋 你的鳃能用
I'm excited. Your gills. They're functional.
大自然的鬼斧神工啊 你能在水里呼吸
Icthyus sapien. You can breathe in the water.
你能潜多深?
How deep can you go? Look, I'm only here...
我来这儿只是想来好好了解下你
Look, l'm only here because I want to learn more about you.
我也不怪你 告诉我
I can't say that I blame you. But tell me:
- 我没有同族 - 噢 那就是鱼式退化
- I have no "kind." - Oh, fish rot.
我好奇地是之前没有 还是现在没有呢
I'd be surprised if there weren't others, and if there aren't,
还是最终会有呢
there will be eventually.
唔 我来是因为有个问题要问你
Anyway, I've come here because I need to ask you a question.
你的泥土从哪儿来的?
Where... Where did your dirt come from?
从陆地来的吗?
Is it from Dryland?
你看得懂这个吗?
Do you know what this is?
古时候的人做了坏事 是不是
The ancients... They did something terrible, didn't they?
才导致了这个满是水的世界 就在几百 好几百年前
To cause all this water. Hundreds... Hundreds of years ago.
如果我告诉了你 你肯开锁吗?
If I tell you, will you open this lock?
我没钥匙
I haven't a key.
- 这下面有一个系缆耳 - 什么?
- There's a mooring cleat down there. - What?
- 那胜过任何钥匙 - 系缆耳?
- Good as any key. - A mooring cleat?
我不会伤害任何人 我只想离开
I won't hurt anyone. I'll just leave.
你在那里干嘛?
What's your business there?
- 快走吧 - 我不是个有胆识的人
- Move along! - I'm not a brave man.
如果你真知道陆地的事 请告诉我 求你了
If you know anything about Dryland, please tell me. Please!
别把它带进坟墓
Don't let it die with you.
不 别 别 别 停下来!
No, no, no, no. Stop!
我们决定这名变种人
it is our decision that this mute-o...
的确对我们造成威胁
does, indeed, constitute a threat.
因此为了公共安全
Therefore, in the interest of public safety,
他被判处回收之刑
he is hereby sentenced to be recycled...
遵照惯例执行
in the customary fashion.
行刑
Proceed.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
化骨为浆
Bones to berries.
抽脉为藤
Veins to vines.
肢骨化为大树 血浆变盐水
His tendons to trees. His blood to brine.
他的生命诡异而怪诞
Too strange for life he was.
变种人即将离我们而去
This mute-o now does leave us,
我们在神明面前收下他的恩泽并铭记他
recycled and entombed, in the presence of him who leads us.
是掠海者 正从太阳的方向攻过来了
Smokers! Dead out of the sun!
大家各就各位
To your posts!
老天啊 偶滴神啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- 大开杀戒 - 进攻
- Kill! - There!
在城墙内很安全
We are safe behind these walls.
是吧?
Aren't we?
放我出来!
Let me out!
让我也出来战斗
Let me out! I'll fight!
传令下去开始攻城
Give me the key to the city now.
我们上 开攻了 开攻了
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
上膛 上膛 快
Floor it! Floor it! Floor it!
快疏通 给我弄通
Swab it! Swab it!
再装子弹
Goddamn! More ammo!
把门撞开来
Break down the door!
老天爷啊!
My God!
Ha!
速战速决拿下这座环礁基地
We'll have this atoll in no time.
转起来!转起来
Crank it! Crank it!
注意!
Look!
当心
Look out!
噢 不要啊
Oh, no!
继续充气 让它们鼓起来
You get that goin'! Fill 'em up!
海伦 快过来
Helen, come quickly!
海伦
Helen!
还没到走的时候
You're not supposed to go yet!
可恶的东西
Infernal machine!
葛雷格 等等
Gregor. Gregor, wait!
海伦 我试过了 出了点儿意外
Helen, I tried. There was an accident.
停不下来了 动作得快点
I can't make it stop. Hurry!
尽全力追上来 跑起来!快点!
You can make it if you try. Run! Up those stairs. Run! Quickly!
- 等等! - 我把绳子扔给你们 跑快点!
- Wait! Wait! - I'll throw you a rope. Run quickly!
- 把绳子丢下来 跑 埃诺拉 对不起
- Throw the rope now. Run, Enola. - Slow down! Wait!
- 把绳子丢下来 不!不! - 等等!
- Throw the rope. No! No! - Wait!
- 葛雷格 别丢下我们! - 噢 不要
- Gregor, don't leave us! - Oh, no!
抱 这完全是个意外
I'm sorry! It was an accident!
海伦 埃诺拉 海伦 对不起
Helen! Enola! Helen, I'm sorry!
射下他 把他射下来
Shoot him. Shoot him.
如果我救你出来了 那你就得带上我们
If I let you out of here, you're taking us with you.
没问题
Sure.
埃诺拉 蹲下
Enola, get down.
呆这儿 呆在这儿 蹲下来
Here. Get over here. Get down.
快点 快
Hurry! Come on!
去把大门打开
Get the gate.
快点
Run!
动作快点
Hurry up!
自杀冲锋队 给我上
Kamikazes. Come on!
炸了个大洞
That made a hole.
快找 抓住那个女孩
Find her! Get the girl!
在那边
There!
快 抓住那家伙 快 灭了他
Go get that guy! Go! Kill him!
- 哇! - 埃诺拉!
- Wow! - Enola!
- 你们俩动作太慢啦 - 到另一边去
- You're too slow! - Run to the other side.
快点
Come on!
抓稳了 坚持住 坚持住
Grab on! Hold on, hold on.
勾住了 我过不去
I'm stuck! I can't make it through!
放开她
Let her go!
就让她掉下来吧
Just drop her!
转那个舵轮 舵轮 转动它
Turn the wheel. The wheel! Turn it!
是那个 快呀 推动它
That! Come on! Push it!
- 我在推呢 - 快!现在拉一下!
- I am! - Hurry! Now pull!
推过去!用力推过去!推过去!
Push it! Push it hard! Push it hard!
好了 好了!现在拉这个!拉它!
Okay, okay! Now pull this! Pull this!
拉起来!快拉
Pull! Pull it! Hurry!
埃诺拉 跳
Enola, jump.
- 看着我 快跳 - 知道啦
- Look at me. Jump! Now! - Okay!
好了 打扰下!
Well, excuse me!
我是不是说过攻击结束前绝不能放任何人走?
Did I say anybody could leave before the battle was over?
- 是不是? - 是的 是的
- Did I? - No! No!
那就行动啊 我恨死了那些帆船
Well, do somethin'. I hate sails.
嘿 你会操作吗?
Hey! Can you steer?
我能相信你吗?
Can I trust you?
谁能告诉我 为什么那艘船还在不停地开火
Answer me this, somebody. Why is that boat still firin'?
- 那伙计叫啥名来着? - 查克
- What's that cousin's name? - Chuck.
- 嘿 查克 - 他正把他的枪口拖向我们这边
- Hey, Chuck! - He's pulling him right into us.
也许他对查克这个叫法没反应
Maybe he doesn't answer to "Chuck."
叫他查尔斯 查尔斯
Call him "Charles." Charles!
让他停下来!叫他停下来
Stop him! Stop him!
查尔斯
Charles!
再见了 伙计们
Adios, cousins.
她一定在这儿 继续找
She's here somewhere. Keep lookin'.
停止!
Stop it!
你搞什么鬼啊?
What you got?
还留了几个活口在那边 但却问不出什么
Couple of heartbeats over there. Aren't sayin' much.
如果你们有注意到这鲜红的血
If you'll notice the arterial nature of the blood
都是从我头上这个窟窿流出来的
comin' from the hole in my head,
你们就应该想到我们今天真得过得很不爽
you can assume that we're all havin' a real lousy day.
所以现在 我要知道有纹身小女孩在哪儿
So here it is: I need to know about that tattooed girl.
谁先说谁就能活命
First one that tells me lives.
我看到一个女孩 我看到
I saw a girl. I saw, I saw...
是 她身上有一个很大的纹身
It was... Sh-She had a big tattoo on her.
你赢了 重新来
You won. Start over.
我看到一个女孩 虽然不是很肯定
I saw a girl. I'm not sure,
但我想她上了那艘有三个船身的船
but I think she got on that boat with three hulls.
就是那艘浪费了我1000千克汽油的船吗
The boat that cost me a thousand G's of go-juice?
是的 那个变种人的船
Yeah, the mute-o's boat.
- 变种人? - 是的 他身上有一些裂缝
- Mute-o? - Yeah. He got these slits here.
就像是鱼鳃一样
Like... Like fish gills.
他不算是地道的人类了
He wasn't really a man.
应该是一个偶然的进化
A fluke of evolution.
噢 抱歉 一个偶然的
Oh, I'm sorry. A fluke of, uh...
- 进化 - 我知道
- Evolution. - I know!
- 不!不要 你说过不会杀我的 - 我说过那话?
- No! No, you said you wouldn't kill me! - Did I say that?
- 有谁听到我说过吗? - 是的 没错 你说过
- Witnesses, anybody, did I? - Yes, yes, yes! You said...
- 你确实说过 - 噢 我可能是说过
- You said it. - Oh, I may have.
可能是说过
I may have.
给飞机加满油 让它出去巡逻
tank up that sky boat; send it out on patrol.
我们得睁大眼
We gotta keep an eye out...
好好留意那个人鱼怪物
for that ichthy-freak.
你到过那儿 对吧?
You been there, haven't you?
陆地?
Dryland?
你知道它的方位
You know where it is.
对 我知道它的方位
Yeah, I know where it is.
那么 我们要去那儿吗?
And, uh... And we're going?
你和我可以
You and I are.
那孩子我们得让她下船
The kid we gotta pitch over the side.
- 什么? - 我的船破了
- What? - My boat's tore up.
我刚堵上了漏洞减少了进水
I'm takin' on water.
幸好我还有那东西能过滤二次淡化水
I'd be lucky to get half a hydro ration out of that.
你知道 我说了我不会喝的
You know... I said I won't drink.
可以坚持整整12天?
For 12 days?
算了吧 最好牺牲你们其中一个
No. It's better one of you dies now...
免得你们死得很痛苦
than both of you die slow.
等一下 等等
Wait. Wait.
我们救了你一命 帮助你逃出生天
We saved your life. We got you out.
不 助我是为了帮你们自己罢了 我们算是扯平了
No, you got me out so you could get out. We're even.
她会煮饭 也会抓鱼
She can cook. She can fish.
- 我也会 - 那我的项链给你 拿着
- So can I. - Then take my necklace. Take my necklace.
- 我在下面能找到更好的 - 别 听着
- I got better ones below. - No, look!
哦
Oh.
在环礁基地经历的一切后
After what you went through back there on the atoll,
我完全明白你想这么做的原因
I can understand why you would want to.
但她还只是个孩子啊
But she's a child.
那还有其他问题了吗
Is there something else then?
埃诺拉 到下面去
Enola! Go below.
埃诺拉
Enola.
是啊 你自己也说了
Yeah. You said so yourself.
出海漂泊很长时间了
Been out there a long time.
几小时之前 我不过是你们眼中值得回收成泥土的家伙
Couple hours ago, I was potential dirt to you.
- 我们并不象那些人 - 你们没差别
- We're not like that. - You all are.
知道我当时真正的想法吗?
Know what I was really thinkin'?
为什么我不趁自己清醒时把你们都扔下海呢
Why I don't drop both of you in my wake right now.
我对你没任何兴趣
You got nothin' I need.
你立马带我们到陆地去
You're taking us to Dryland.
杀人可没那么简单
Killing's a hard thing to do well.
- 相信我 要杀我就更不容易了 - 我们也是
- Believe me. I'm not the one to start on. - Both of us!
你打算用那玩意儿指着我多久?
How long you plan to hold that on me?
需要多久就多久
As long as it takes.
- 那好吧 - 不!
- Okay. - No!
放我出去
Let me out of here!
该死的你在哪儿呢 别碰我的孩子
Where the hell are you? Don't you touch my child.
过来啊
Come here!
好了 现在别动了 明白吗?很好
Okay, now don't move, okay? There.
看起来真不错 真的
Ohh. Oh, lookin' real good, yeah.
好了 好了
There. There.
搞定了
All done.
就现状而言 在视觉的深度上可能会有一点小问题
Now, there may be some small problem in depth perception.
是吗 它最好别影响到我击近球技术[高尔夫]
Well, it better not screw up my short game.
- 怎么样? - 很酷 我喜欢 是啊
- Well? - Looks good. I like it. Yeah.
- 我觉得它比你的真眼还好看 - 好看多了
- I like it better than your real eye. - Much better.
- 你觉得呢 多碧? - 说实话像狗屎一样
- What do you say, Toby? The truth. - Looks like shit.
这就是我喜欢孩子的原因 不会说谎
That's why I love children. No guile.
真的像狗屎一样
It does look like shit.
感觉更像冰狗屎
And it feels like cold shit!
帝刚?什么事?
Deacon? What...
抱歉 只是深井那边出了点状况
I'm sorry. L-lt's just that there's a problem in the pit.
可能需要您摆驾前去看看
Maybe you should come.
起驾
Let's drive.
到深井 别惊动了沿途的那些美景
The pit. Don't bother with the scenic route.
走啦!
Drive!
嘿 这开起来顺手多了
Hey, it's drivin' better.
滚开点儿
Get off!
闪开 别占道
Get over there. Get out of the way.
好吧 行了 行了 好吧 好吧
All right, all right, all right. Okay, okay.
祝福你们 兄弟们 祝福你们 祝福所有的兄弟们
You guys are great. Bless all you cousins over there.
继续努力 有成长就有进步 继续努力 继续努力
Keep up the good work. Growth is progress. Growth is progress.
有人吗? 嘿 上面的
Somebody! Hey, up there!
把井盖打开
Take it off!
- 什么事? - 帝刚大人
- Yes. - Your Deaconship.
你好 早上好 或者该晚上好
Hello. Good morning. Or night,
管它的
whichever the case may be.
- 有什么事?我是大忙人 - 我想应该通知您了
- What is it? I'm a busy man. - I thought you should know.
准确算来我们只剩下
We're down to exactly...
4尺9寸深的柏油了
four feet, nine inches of black stuff.
十分感谢 老大
Thank you, sir.
经过提炼之后能有多少千克?
How many G's is that after refinin'?
可能能灌满三个加油器
Maybe three refuelers.
- 够我们用上两个月 - 亲爱的乔
- We'll burn through that in two lunars. - Sweet Joe!
谁能告诉我这个地方到底怎么了
Will somebody please tell me what's happened to this place?
供需太不平衡了
We outgrowed it.
好了 现在最重要的就是那个有纹身的小姑娘
All right, the only thing that is important is the tattooed girl.
我们不可能为了省油而不去找她
We don't spare any go-juice findin' her.
那么在其他地方就别再浪费了
We don't waste it anywhere else.
你们去关掉所有的牵引车
You cancel all those tractor pulls...
和其他耗油的东西
and all that stuff until later.
听懂了吗?
You got it?
陆地可是块沃土啊
Dryland is the mother lode.
打起精神来
On your toes.
太好了
Excellent.
- 嗨 - 闪开
- Hi. - Move.
埃诺拉 埃诺拉 过来
Enola! Enola, come here!
快点
Come on!
埃诺拉 到这边来
Enola, come over here.
嘿
Hey!
- 你在干嘛呢? - 给你船好好打扮一下 它太丑了
- What are ya doin'? - Decorating your boat. It's ugly.
- 你在哪儿拿来的? - 下面拿来的
- Where did you get this? - From down below.
这是我的 别碰我的东西
This is mine! You don't touch anything of mine.
我是为你画的
I drew it for you.
不需要你画任何东西 听明白了吗?
You don't draw on anything. You understand?
什么?
What...
这是我的船 就得按我的喜好来
This is my boat. I got it the way I like it.
你们占了我的空间还拖慢了我的速度
You take up space and you slow me down.
她只是个小姑娘而言
You know, she's just a little girl.
- 还不懂你的规矩 - 想留在船上?
- She doesn't know your rules. - You wanna stay?
就好好教教她
You teach her.
埃诺拉 我对你说过什么来着?
Enola, what'd I tell you?
你根本不是这么铁石心肠的 你自己清楚?
You're not so tough. You know that?
你杀过多少人?
How many people have you killed?
12?还是20个?
Ten? Twenty?
- 你很聒噪啊 - 我聒噪是因为你几乎都一言不发的
- You talk a lot. - I talk a lot 'cause you don't talk at all.
多少个?
Now how many?
- 包括小女孩吗? - 我才不怕你
- Including little girls? - I'm not afraid of you.
我跟海伦说过如果你剪剪头发就不会这么难看了
I told Helen you wouldn't be so ugly if you cut your hair.
知道吗 你老是说个不停
In fact, you talk all the time.
- 让人就像陷入了风暴里一样 - 埃诺拉
- It's like a storm when you're around. - Enola!
嘿 你在干嘛?
Hey! What are you doing?
- 海伦 - 你这浑球 她不会游泳
- Helen! - You bastard! She can't swim!
救救我!海伦
Help me! Helen!
海伦 救救我
Helen, help me!
海伦
Helen!
海伦 救救我
Helen, help me!
海伦!海伦
Helen! Helen!
坚持住
Hold on!
看着我 看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.
求求你 回来 拜托了
Oh, please, come back. Please!
拜托!噢 拜托了!
Please! Oh, please!
嘿!
Hey!
坚持住 行了 没事了
Hold on. Okay, almost...
那里
there.
谢谢 我发誓
Thanks. I swear,
如果你在碰她的话
if you ever touch her again...
浑球 转过来
You son of a bitch. Look at me.
只要你会上床睡觉那你永远也别想醒了
You will go to bed that night, and you will never wake up.
- 闭嘴 - 怎么了?
- Shut up. - What?
- 是掠海者吗 - 对
- Smokers? - Yeah.
我们能避开他们吗?
Can't we outrun them?
除非我没收帆
Not with my sail down.
- 你犯什么傻呢? - 多友好地挥手啊
- What are you thinkin' about? - That's a nice touch.
是他们
That's them.
别伤了那孩子
Don't hit the kid.
嘿!
Hey!
你个懦夫
Coward!
可恶
Fuck!
住手
No!
切断它
Cut it!
加油 加油啊
Come on! Come on!
好吧 好吧
All right. Okay.
真的很抱歉
Oh, I'm really sorry.
真抱歉 你让我别无选择
I'm sorry. But you didn't give me much choice.
我知道
Oh, I know.
你开溜了 我 要干嘛?
But you ran away. L... What?
你要干嘛 别 求你了 不要啊
What are you do... No! Please, no! No!
永远别再碰我船上的任何东西了
Don't ever touch anything on my boat again.
她已经向你道歉了
She said she was sorry!
意味着你应该有所回应才对
That means you're supposed to say something back!
你在说话吗?
Did you say somethin'?
那个孩子 他带着那个女孩吗?
The child... did he have the girl with him?
- 对 - 如果我们马上出发的话
- Uh-huh. - Seems to me if we launch now,
我们大概可以在这里截住他
we can cut him down just about here.
- 只要他不改变航道的话 - 那不可能
- If he doesn't change course. - Ah, it's not likely.
他很狡猾的 那个臭鱼人
He's a wily one, that ichthy-demon.
如果他知道自己已经被发现了
Yeah, if he knows he's been spotted,
他可能推测我们必定认为他改变了航向
he'll expect us to expect him to change course,
所以他一定不会改变航向
which is exactly why he'll keep his heading.
重点是 他这是要去哪儿
The important question is, where's he heading?
以及他清楚自己船上的货物价值吗
And does he know how precious his cargo is?
他正向这儿赶 我们就在这儿拦截他
I say that he's headed here, and we take him here.
- 浪人? - 对
- Drifter? - Mm-hmm.
我们要停下来吗?
Are we gonna stop?
- 看那旗子 - 他升起旗子
- Look at the flag! - His flag's up.
我以为你们都互相帮助
I thought you all stopped for each other.
也许他有食物
Well... maybe he has some food!
大家都不守规矩了
Don't find many who follow the rules anymore.
有话快说 你想干嘛?
Well, make it quick. What's your business?
交换东西
Trade.
你有树脂吗?
You got any resin?
树脂?那是我的 全是我的
Resin? He's gotta be out of his mind. He's out of his mind. I don't have any resin.
你在海上很久了 对吧?
You been outwater a long time, haven't you?
是取笑我吧 哈 树脂 你的东西可不够换啊
Must be jokin' me, man. Resin! You don't got enough.
有食物吗?
How 'bout food?
能请你再说一次吗
Could you say that again, please?
- 有食物吗? - 啊 有 食物
- How 'bout food? - Ah, yeah, food.
是啊 要有食物就好了
Yeah, that'd be good, eh?
我都没吃过 知道吗 已经好长时间了
I haven't eaten in, well, you know, forever.
你们哪个是厨子?
Which one of you two is a cook?
因为我通常喜欢泡女服务生
'Cause I usually fall for the waitress.
像你说的 我没多少东西
Like you said, I don't have much.
听着 让我看看 那边那些植物如何?
Now listen, eh? Let's see. What do I have to do?
我们可以从你那边那个迷你的小果园开始
We can start with that wee orchard you got over there.
好了 呆在那儿别动
All right, hold it there.
- 咱们谈谈 - 可以
- We can talk. - Fair enough.
真是漂亮的竹竿 不是吗?
It's a nice rod, isn't it?
我很喜欢 钓竿很棒
I like that rod. It's a nice rod.
你这儿可真是妻妾成群啊 不是吗
Got yourself a wee harem goin' here now, do ya?
这女人怎么卖?
What you want for the women?
我们不是拿来卖的
We're not for sale.
非卖品?根本不存在非卖品
Not for sale? There's no such thing as not for sale.
非卖品 是非卖品吗
"Not for sale"! Not for sale, eh?
- 成双卖 还是分开卖 - 不
- Are they a pair or would you consider sellin' 'em separate? - No.
除非你能有树脂或船帆可以交换
Our business is done here unless you got some resin for sale you can part with.
我已经告诉你了 我没有那些
I told you once already, I don't have it.
我没有 没有 没有
I- I-I don't have it. Don't have it. Don't have it.
已经好几个月没见到半个人来交意了 等等 先等等
Haven't seen neither for trade in lunars now. Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
我确实有些能让你改变想法东西
I do have somethin' that'll make you change your mind.
让你无法抗拒的东西
Somethin' that you can't pass on.
我从一个难民环礁基地弄来的
I took it off an Atoller refugee camp.
是整个氏族一辈子的积蓄
The life savings of the entire clan.
纸张
Paper.
这可是纸啊 你见过纸吗?你看看
It's paper. Have you ever seen paper? Look at it.
闻闻看
Smell it.
我一直珍藏着就是为了特别交易
I been savin' it for a special trade.
别这么做
Don't you do it.
我是不是找错谈判对象了啊
You know, maybe I'm talkin' to the wrong person here.
这艘船到底是谁的?究竟是你的船还是你的呢?
Whose boat is this? Is it your boat or your boat?
不 不 船是他的 但我们不是他的
No. No, it's his boat. But he doesn't own us.
半小时
Half an hour.
他疯啦还是怎么了
Out of his mind somethin' there.
我用这个至少能换个半打姑娘 你知道吗?
I got two pages in here, man! I mean, I'd get half a dozen girls with this, you know.
就半小时
Half an hour.
- 要不要随你 - 别这样
- You tradin' or not? - Don't.
闭嘴
Shut up.
好吧
Okay.
不然换45分钟跟那边那个幼齿吧
Forty-five minutes with the wee one right there.
我更中意调教幼齿 你该明白的?
I like to do the talkin', if you know what I mean.
不行
No!
好吧 快过来 来 来 来 来啊
Fair. Come, come, come, come, come!
不 就在我的船上
No. My boat.
- 可以 可以 好的 好的 当然没问题 - 海伦
- Fair enough. Fair enough. Good, good, good. Aye. - Helen.
- 坐下来 - 埃诺拉 乖乖听他的话
- Sit down. - Enola, just do as he says.
这对现在的我而言只算得上一小会儿
It's been a while for me now.
但事实上 那却又不止一小会儿
Guess it's been more than a while, actually.
我只有半个小时 半个小时 半个小时啊
I've only got half an hour.Half an hour, half an hour, half an hour...
对了 对了 很好
Great, great, great...
你好美 有人这么称赞过你吗?
Ooh! You're so beautiful. Aye! Anyone ever told you that?
少来这套 你这是在干嘛?不就是睡一觉嘛
Give me that. What are you doin'? It's just a game.
我 我 我们刚刚只是想跟她玩玩
Oh, I, um... I, uh... We was just playin'.
不换了
The trade's off.
我改变主意
I changed my mind.
你不能反悔
Well, um... Well, you can't do that.
都已经成交了啊
I mean, a deal's a deal, eh?
我说了反悔了
I just did.
嘿
Hey!
她已经是我的了 不 不 我还没碰到她呢 不行
She's mine. Aye. No. No, no I own her. But... No.
- 走吧 - 行啊 行啊 走吧 走吧 很好 很好
- Go on. - Get, get, get. Go, go, go. Good, good.
别走得太远 这耽搁不了一分钟
But don't go too far now. This won't take but a minute.
我恨这艘船 我恨透了这条船
I hate this boat. I hate this boat!
你这浑球
You bastard.
对于拥有这么多东西的人来说你真是抠到家了
You... You're pretty stingy for a man who's got everything, aren't ya now?
你这浑球
Ah, you bastard!
我的船在哪儿啊?
Where's me boat?
我的小船呢?
带我到船上
Help me to me boat.
我的船
Ow! Me boat.
Me boat.
想干嘛 别!
What the... No!
用这个根本抓不到任何东西 就是个废物
Never catch anything with this. It's useless.
听着 我道歉 你说得很对 那竿子是废物
Look, I'm sorry. You were right about the pole.
你说得对是对 但我们还是得吃东西啊
You were right, but we have to eat.
嘿 别装聋作哑的
Now I know you can hear me!
我们可以自己抓鱼来吃 但至少你得告诉我们该怎么做
Now we can fish for ourselves. You show us what to do.
你要知道 即使是你也要吃东西的
You must know how. Even you gotta eat!
你们俩乖乖给我坐着
You just sit there.
- 什么玩意?... - 我不知道
- What... - I don't know.
满足了?
Happy now?
你不喜欢我哼歌 对吧?
You don't like my singing, do you?
听海伦说你之所以讨厌我唱歌是因为你不能唱
Helen says you don't like my singing 'cause you can't sing.
- 你试着聆听过吗? - 听什么?
- Ever try and listen? - To what?
世界之音
The sound of the world.
- 我什么也听不到 - 那是因为你整天都吵个不停
- I don't hear anything. - That's because you're too loud,
你老是动个不停
and you're movin' around all the time.
静下来试试
Try sittin' still.
来颗鱼眼?
Eyeball?
我也想要他那样的脚
I wish I had feet like his.
也许我就能游泳了
Then maybe I could swim.
埃诺拉
Enola.
抱歉
Sorry.
我之前还从来没有见过不会游泳的人
Never met a person couldn't swim before.
我就不会
I can't.
别人都说我是个怪胎
People say I was weird.
也许确如他们所说
Maybe they were right.
也许你也确如他们所说
Maybe they were right about you too.
埃诺拉要把这个还给你
Enola wanted to give you this.
还有这个
And this.
她以后不会再拿了
She won't take it again.
你跟她长得不太像
You don't look much like her.
我不是她的生母
Well, I'm not her mother,
如果你想知道的是这个的话
if that's what you're asking.
你却视她如亲生一样
You act like it.
她背上那些图是什么?
What are those marks on her back?
没什么 只是好看而已
Nothing. They're just fanciful things.
- 她画的那些也是吗? - 她只画她见过得的东西
- Like what she draws? - She draws what she sees.
她就如一面镜子
She's like a mirror.
大家一度认为都认为她是…
People on the atoll thought she was a...
怪胎?
Freak?
对
Uh-huh. Yeah.
我却认为她很特别
I just thought she was special.
我并不是要给她 只是...
I'm not givin' it to her. It's just...
借她用
A loan.
对 我不是给她
Yeah. I'm not givin' it to her.
陆地很美吗?
Is Dryland beautiful?
你会亲眼所见的
You'll see.
埃诺拉
Enola?
埃诺拉 你在干嘛?
Enola, what are you doing?
- 那些怪物会杀了她的 - 它们都在睡觉
- Those monsters'll kill her! - No, they're asleep now.
抱住我的脖子
Hands around my neck.
让你的手和脚在水的带领下动起来
Let the water tell your arms and legs how to move.
我们要潜下去 憋住呼吸
We're goin' down. Hold your breath.
- 怎么了? - 那是什么?
- What is it? - What is it?
易物交易的前哨站
Barter outpost.
你说我们今天会到达陆地的
You said we'd get to Dryland today.
今天 明天 都无所谓
Today. Tomorrow. What's it matter?
我需要树脂
I need resin.
- 那是什么话? - 是葡希文 他们自己的语言
- What is that? - It's PortuGreek. Their own language.
不然就是如我所料
Or so I thought.
呃
Ah.
- 那就是我要的小姑娘 - 是啊
- There's my girl. - Yeah.
您好啊 小可爱 快到我们怀抱里来吧
Howdy, darlin'. Come on in here now.
- 怎么回事? - 是掠海者
- What's going on? - Smokers.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
穿帮了快发信号
He's spotted us. Sound it!
发信号快发信号快发信号
Sound it! Sound it! Sound it! Sound it!
噢哦
Yahoo!
埃诺拉
Enola!
到右舷去马上
Starboard side! Now!
站到椅子上
Get in the chair!
注意他入网了
Watch it. He's clearin' the net.
你去掌舵
Go to the helm.
- 把舯板打开 - 舯板?
- Get the centerboard! - Centerboard?
- 舯板是啥? - 到底是要我做什么?
What centerboard? I don't know what to do!
太迟了 快过来
It's too late. Over here!
不是吧
No!
来福枪拿来 想做好一件事
Gimme that rifle. Boy, if you wanna do somethin' right,
自己动手才能丰衣足食
you've got to do it yourself.
好的
All right.
- 我打到他了 - 我说我们...
- I winged him. - I say we load...
快点派一艘船去逮那怪物
all the go-juice onto one boat and run the freak down.
你派了十艘都没能抓住他 你还想一艘就能得逞
You can't catch him in ten boats, and you wanna send just one?
你是在讲冷笑话吧
Well, I pray that you're jokin'.
把追踪器给我拿来
Bring me the trackers.
他受伤了
He's hurt.
他们不是来抓她
It's not what you think. They weren't after her.
- 我是亲眼所见 - 什么意思?
- I saw what I saw. - What?
别再跟我撒谎了
No more lies.
她背上的究竟是什么
What are the marks on her back?
大家都说那是通往陆地的指示
People say it's the way to Dryland.
陆地只是个神话
Dryland's a myth!
不可能 你自己说过你知道它在哪儿的
No! You said so yourself that you know where it is.
你说过
You did.
你居然蠢得去相信见都没见过的东西
You're a fool to believe in something you've never seen before.
我不光见过 我更摸过
I've seen it. I've touched it!
那泥土比你带来的更肥沃 色泽更深
Dirt that was richer and darker than yours.
就在发现埃诺拉的那个篮子里
It was in the basket we found Enola in!
- 那根本就不存在 - 你凭什么那么肯定?
- It doesn't exist! - Well, how can you be so sure?
因为我的航程早已远过了那些梦想之地 而我却从未见到过
Because I've sailed farther than most have dreamed, and I've never seen it.
但你船上的那些东西呢
But the things on your boat!
我船上的东西 指什么?
"Things on my boat" what?
你船上那些个没人见过的东西
There are things on your boat that nobody has ever seen!
像这些贝壳呐?
What are these shells?
还有那个反光镜啊
And that reflecting glass?
以及那个音乐盒 那个
And th-the music box? That...
那不是陆地来的 那是哪儿来的呢?哪儿来的?
Well, if not from Dryland, then where? Wh-Where?
你想看陆地吗?
You wanna see Dryland?
你真的那么想看吗?
You really wanna see it?
我就带你到陆地
I'll take you to Dryland.
下水
Get in.
- 埃诺拉怎么办? - 这儿的空气只够一个人用
- Well, what about Enola? - There's only air for one.
- 快下来 - 没事的
- Get in the water. - It'll be all right.
别乱来啊?
Don't touch anything.
好了吗?
Okay?
真没想到
I didn't know.
这么久以来
All this time...
真没想到
I didn't know.
没有人知道
Nobody does.
我们逃得掉吗?
Can you get us outta here?
要我说倒是两种可能性
I'd say there're two chances o' that.
- 嘿! - 那就是无处可逃 无计可施
- Hey! - No way and no how.
早就叫你请我喝一杯的 上来
Shoulda bought me that drink. Come on!
上来 快
This way. Come on!
首先正式地自我介绍一下
Proper introductions first.
我就是帝刚
I'm the Deacon.
如果不记得我这张脸了 可能是
If you don't recall the face, perhaps it's
因为之前我的脸可并不是这个样子
'cause I didn't always look like this.
我一直在猜她到底躲在哪里
Now, ahem, I suspect she's somewhere real close.
为了找到她 我们不得不痛心地拆了这艘船
So we can tear this boat apart lookin' for her,
但是我更希望有人能告诉我她躲在哪儿
but I'd rather somebody tell me where she is.
谁先说谁就能活下来
And the first one that does that, lives.
而亚军就 事实上 压根就不会有亚军
And the runner-up... Well, actually, there are no runners-up.
哦 亲爱的乔 这可是我的最爱
Oh, sweet Joe, I love this part.
自己挑吧 第一名还是第二 生还是死
Choose 'em. One, two. Live or die.
就我个人而言
You know, personally,
我更喜欢留下你来好好享用
I'd rather shoot the sperm-of-the-devil here.
但就算你知道
Huh? But you know somethin'?
我想你也不会告诉我的 对吗?
I don't think you're gonna tell me, are ya?
真遗憾
Huh? Too bad.
好了 有什么要说的吗
Come on, eh? What do you say?
她又不是你同类
She's not your kind.
你根本就没有同类吧
You don't even have a kind.
你告诉了他 他还是会杀了我们俩
If you say it, he'll still kill us both.
咱就别相互为难彼此了
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
如果你不说
If you don't tell me,
我以波塞冬海神之名起誓我一定烧了你的船
I swear to Poseidon I will torch your boat.
提醒我一下 之前遇到这种情况时是怎么做的来着?
Refresh my memory. What happens when neither of 'em talks?
- 从没遇到过 - 从没遇到过
- Never happened before. - Never happened before.
好啊
All right!
如果他们不说 就干掉他们
If they won't tell us where she is, do 'em! Both of 'em! Kill 'em now!
- 不要 - 不要
- No! - No!
真好骗 把她带过来
So gullible! Bring her here.
- 到手了 - 不 放开她!
Take and ye shall receive! - No! Leave her!
今天的布道就到此结束啦
So ends your daily sermonette!
我们只要能搞懂这个地图就成了 把她倒过来衣服揭开
All we gotta do is figure out this map. Turn her upside down.
- 你看得明白吗? - 不明白
- Does that mean anything to you? - No.
回帝斯号去慢慢琢磨 兄弟们 打道回府了
We'll figure it out back at the 'Deez. Back at the 'Deez, boys.
好好看着她 小心点
Careful with her. Careful with her!
- 他们呢? - 两个都干掉
- What about them? - Do 'em both.
船也烧了
Torch the boat.
我们得潜下水
We have to go under!
不行 我不象你能在水下呼吸
No, I can't breath like you!
我可以让我们俩同时呼吸
I'll breathe for both of us.
海伦
Helen!
海伦 救救我!海伦 海伦
Helen, help! Helen! Helen!
我的船
My boat.
埃诺拉
Enola.
这算什么?把她的镣铐解开
What is this? Get those chains off her.
怎么?我们是野蛮人吗?
What are we, barbarians here?
我的老天啊 太没人性了
Goodness gracious. Sakes alive.
快滚 滚出去 你这个又肥又讨厌的东西
Come on. Outta here, you big, nasty animal, you!
Well rub-a-dub-dub.
要过来坐我的大腿上吗?
You wanna come over here and sit on my lap?
不要?
No? Ahem.
来根香烟如何?
How 'bout a cigarette?
抽根香烟快乐似神仙
Nothin' like a good smoke if you miss your mom.
多小开始抽都没关系
Never too young to start.
不要 好吧 有些东西我知道你一定喜欢
No. Well, I got somethin' right here I know you'd like.
你很喜欢画画 对吧?
Like to draw, don't you? Huh?
他们都可以给你
Huh? Now they're yours...
只要你帮我一个忙 行吗?
if you help me with just one problem, all right?
你背上的那个纹身
Now, ahem... Now that tattoo on your back... Ahem.
我听说那似乎是一份地图是吗 听说那其实是地图
I've been told that, uh... that's actually a map?
那是通向陆地的指示
It's the way to Dryland.
看来我们找到地方了
Now we're gettin' someplace.
你能教我怎么看吗?
Could you teach me how to read that?
功亏一篑啊
Setback.
那你曾听你的哪位朋友讨论过那个纹身吗
Well, have you ever heard any of your friends talk about it?
比如你妈妈或者是你的宠物鱼叔叔 他说过什么吗?
You know, like your mommy or your pet fish? Did he say anything?
你不该嘲笑他的 他会不高兴的
You shouldn't make fun of him. He wouldn't like it.
我才不管他喜不喜欢 他弄瞎了我的一只眼
Girl, I don't give a shit what he'd like. He took out my eye.
如果再让我看到他 我一定要开他的脑吸干他的脑髓
And if I ever see him again, I'm gonna cut open his head and eat his brains!
他会喜欢那样吗
You think he'd like that?
根本杀不了他他可比你狠多了
Can't kill him. He's even meaner than you are.
但他不在这儿
But he's not here.
更不会来这儿
And he ain't comin'.
所以根本没人会来救你
And no one's gonna save you.
他一定会来救我的 一定会
He'll come for me. He will.
那你最好乖乖地从实招来
Then you better tell me what I wanna know
否则他能救到的只会是个尸骨无存的你
or he can see what's left of you in a goddamn jar.
我们死定了 对不对?
We're going to die here, aren't we?
是吗?
Aren't we?
逃出环礁基地后
After the atoll,
我曾要献身给你
when I offered myself to you,
你当时为什么会拒绝呢?
why didn't you take me?
因为你并不是真得想要我
'Cause you didn't really want me.
你不是自愿的
Not really.
我睡了很久吗?
Have I been asleep long?
我做了个梦
I was dreaming.
很奇怪
It's funny.
我一直以为陆地是漂浮着的
I always thought Dryland floated.
它会随风而动 所以才那么难找
That it drifted with the wind.
为什么你会如此地深信不疑
That's why it was so hard to find.
你为什么深信有陆地?
Why did you believe in it so much?
因为我们根本无法在海洋中生存
Because we weren't made for the sea.
看看我们的手和脚
Got hands... and feet.
那是用来行走的
We're supposed to walk.
我好想念她的声音
I miss her sound.
你呢?
Don't you?
海伦
Helen!
不 不对 不对 海伦 抬头 你头上
He... No, no, no. Helen, up here. Above you!
葛雷格
Gregor!
很机灵啊 烧了你们的船
Smart thinking to burn your boat.
要不是看到了浓烟 我永远都无法找到你们
Without the smoke, I never would have found you.
和你一起的那家伙是谁
Who's that with you?
那个鱼神?真的是你吗?
Ichthyus Sapien, is that really you?
我把绳子扔给你们 抓牢了 我把你们拉上来
I'll throw the rope down. You catch it. I'll help you climb up.
海伦 埃诺拉呢?
Helen. Where's Enola?
被掠海者抓走了 幸好有他在 我才幸免于难
Smokers took her. They'd have me too if it weren't for him.
我的朋友 谢谢你 你非常地有人性
My friend, thank you. Very human of you.
快把你们的东西拿上 动作快 快
Go grab your things quickly. Quickly. Come.
看到了吗?就在这下面
You see? Right down there.
那是基地的一些幸存者 我们正准备重新开始
There's several of us survivors. We'll just start over again.
你不能要求我们都去救她
You can't ask us to go get her!
埃诺拉正是这场劫难的根源
Enola's the reason we're in all this trouble.
反正他们又不会杀了她 他们跟我们一样在找陆地
They don't have any reason to kill her. They need to find Dryland just like we do.
- 毫无疑问 - 连那个浪行者都愿意去了 我们怎么能无动于衷呢
- Of course. - If the Mariner's willing to go, why not us?
他愿意就让他去呀
If he wants to go, then let him!
我们根本不想收留你们 你和那个女孩都是
We don't want you here! You or the girl!
海伦 那个航海人给你的这些纸纸
Helen. The papers the Mariner brought you...
上面的文字和纹身上面的文字是同一种语言 上面有号码
It's the same language the tattoo is written in. They're numbers.
- 葛雷格 你和她一样疯狂 - 我们不能呆在这儿
- Gregor, you're as crazy as she is! - We can't stay here!
我们再不抓紧时间
We're wasting valuable time.
更多的掠海者就会追来了
More Smokers will come.
我们需要马上转移
We need to be moving now!
我的朋友们 你们还不明白吗 想要找到陆地我们就需要那个孩子
My friends, don't you see we need this child if we want to find Dryland?
- 我才不会去呢 - 谁都不去
- I'm not goin'. - Nobody is.
我们远远就看到他们的烟
We've seen their smoke on the horizon!
- 搞懂那个是什么了吗? - 这些数字吗?当然 我想我搞懂了
- Know what that is yet? - The numbers? Yes, I think I do.
这看起来应该是过去的地理坐标 是纬度和经度
It seems to be some ancient form of geographic location: Latitude, longitude.
不过 有点不合理 这些数字 似乎是颠倒的还是怎么了
It doesn't make sense, though. The numbers, they seem to be backwards or something.
- 确实是颠倒的 - 整个世界吗?
- It's upside down. - The world?
两级也是颠倒的?
The poles have reversed themselves?
我一直在勘测水下的城市
I've been mappin' the cities below.
世界并不是在水中建起的 而是被水淹没了
The world wasn't created in a deluge. It was covered by it.
- 那话简直是亵渎神灵 - 不 那是事实
- That's blasphemy! - No, it's true.
我亲眼所见那些土地就在我们身下这片海底
I've seen it with my own eyes. There is land. It's right under our keel.
- 根本就没有干地 - 有些是
- None of it's dry anymore. - Some is.
埃诺拉确实曾到过那儿 在看到她画得那些画之后 我很肯定
Enola's been there. I know that now. I saw what she drew.
所以你是为了陆地找她
So that's why he's going after Enola... to find Dryland.
我才不管陆地
I don't care about Dryland.
真是太荒谬可笑了 要怎么找掠海者啊
This is ridiculous. Going after the Smokers?
他连他们打哪儿来的都不知道
He doesn't even know which direction they came from.
- 我说让他走吧 - 没有他更好
- I say let him go. - We're better off without them anyway!
只要她还活着 我就一定把她带回来
If she's alive, I'll bring her back to you.
得了 别管那个变种人了 海伦别 如果他带她回来我们都会死
Forget the mute-o, Helen. If he brings her back, they'll kill us!
我不能袖手旁观 我们得去帮帮他 不能让他一个人冒险
I can't stand it. We gotta go help him. I can't ask him to do this alone.
噢 放心吧 亲爱的 你想去的话简单得多
Oh, don't worry, my dear. You're not going to have to.
你们搞懂纹身的涵义了吗?
You got that tattoo figured out yet?
如果再平整点就容易多了 最好又大又平整
It would be easier if it was flat... big and flat.
- 这得摊平了来看 - 你到底想干嘛?
- It needs to be flat. - What you got in mind?
最好能从她背上割下来 就可以摊平了 甚至裱起来
Well, you cut it off her back. You stretch it, mount it.
- 我们就能慢慢研究了 - 把她带下去等我叫她
- Give us a proper look. - Take her down below until I holler.
伟大的乔 就要到头了
Saint Joe, we're close.
在经历了几世纪的屈辱之后
After centuries of shame.
- 他们开始有点暴躁了 - 听出来了
- They're gettin' ugly. - Don't I know it.
可以开始了 兄弟
Announce me, cousin.
注意了 他来了
Hey. Here he is.
帝刚
Deacon!
热情点 兄弟姐妹们起来
Rise up, brothers and sisters.
睁开你们的双眼打开胸襟
Turn your eyes and open your hearts...
你们仁慈的布施者
to your humble benefactor,
你们灵魂的引导者 命运的依托者
your spiritual shepherd and dictator for life,
帝斯号的帝刚
the Deacon of the 'Deez.
- 当心! - 是我的!是我的!
- Look out! - It's mine! It's mine!
- 帝刚 - 哇
- Deacon! - Wahoo!
孩子们 我可爱的孩子们
Children. Children of the provider.
帝斯号的好船民 安静下来听我说
Citizens of the good ship. Please now, hear me speak.
- 我见到了一个幻象 - 我们已经受够了你的那些幻象了
- I've had a vision. - Yeah, we're tired of your visions!
你对我们许诺过的土地在哪儿呢
What about the land you promised us?
是啊!是啊
Yeah! Yeah!
你们对信仰太不坚定了
Oh ye of little faith.
我看到的这个幻象如此美好
I've had a vision so great...
美好到让我感激涕零
that as it came to me, I wept.
- 让我以为那只是南柯一梦 - 这不是波恩的摩托艇吗?
- And in this splenditudinous figment of wonder, - Is that Bone's ride?
- 座位上是血迹吗 - 我见到的
- Is that blood on the seat? - I saw...
你知不知道我看到了什么
And you know what it is that I saw.
我看到...陆地
I saw... the land.
霍斯 是你吗?
Horse, that you?
慢慢的开进来 别浪费时间
Look, just bring it in slow, okay? I don't have all day.
霍斯
Horse!
慢慢开进来
Just bring it up slow.
慢慢开进来!
I said slow!
你不应该这样 你会惹麻烦
Shouldn't be doing that. You're gonna get in trouble.
是啊 是啊
Ha. That's right.
而你没有害怕 因为你在期盼着你那可爱的怪物叔叔来救你
You're not afraid. You've got your pet freak comin' to rescue you.
他才不是怪物呢 他随时都能要了你的命
He's not a freak, and he can take you anytime.
他杀人无数 冷血无情 更不会心慈手软
He's killed dozens of people, and he doesn't have any mercy or anything.
他连小女孩都杀
He even kills little girls.
难道我们就会吗
Haven't we all?
该死的
Shit.
是霍斯
It's Horse.
- 去找他 去找他 - 快
- Find him. Find him! - Come on!
是的!是的!是的!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
- 快来 - 有点紧张了 是吗?
- Come on. - Gettin' nervous, aren't you?
我不会紧张
I don't get nervous.
如果有河 我们就建坝蓄水
And if there's a river, we'll dam it.
如果有树 我们就大兴土木
And if there's a tree, we'll ram it.
因为此刻我说的可是发展
'Cause I'm talkin' progress here.
是的 我说的是开拓
Yes, sir. I'm talkin' development.
- 是的 - 因为我们马上就能尽情地舔吸
- Yeah! - For we shall suck and savor...
陆地的沁人芬芳
the sweet flavor of Dryland.
你的脸已经都红了
Face is all red.
海伦说过如果有人的脸红得已经成了关公那样
Helen said with anybody that has a face that red,
那他不是晒得太久就是喝多了
he's had too much sun or too much to drink.
行了 我受够了 看我不毁了你的小脸蛋儿
All right, that's it. I'm gonna burn your face.
时间刚刚好
Almost time.
- 怎么了? - 只不过是刚刚聊起了她朋友
- What's up? - We're just talkin' about our friend.
- 他叫什么名字? - 她没有名字
- What's his name? - He doesn't have a name.
所以死神无法找到他
So death can't find him.
他无亲无故 没有任何后顾之忧
Doesn't have a home or people to care for.
他浑身是胆 无所畏惧
He's not afraid of anything, men least of all.
他就像飓风一样强大而迅猛
He's fast and strong like a big wind.
在水下他更是来去自如
He can hear a hundred miles and see a hundred miles underwater.
他能躲在太阳阴影下
He can hide in the shadow of the noon sun.
他可以潜伏在你身后 你死了都不知道
He could be right behind you, and you won't even know it 'til you're dead!
让你的嘴歇歇
Give it a rest.
他会来救我的 一定会
He'll come for me. He will.
- 我们就是开拓先锋 - 是吗?
- We are the people... - Yeah?
- 希望如此 - 这是神的恩泽
- Well, I hope he does. - The Lord's creation.
记住你说过这句话
Remember you said that.
瞧瞧我们
Look at us.
- 好好看看今天还在这里的我们 - 是的
- Look at us here today. - Yeah!
陆地不仅仅是我们的梦之地
Dryland is not just our destination,
也是我们的命运
but it is our destiny!
快去找他 把她找出来!
Find him. Find him!
我该怎么找到
How can I find...
这片乐土
this glorious place?
他对我说
And he said to me:
你将遇见一个孩子
"A child shall lead you."
一个孩子
A child.
- 看哪 - 是时候了
- And behold! - It's time.
我们的救星
The instrument of our salvation!
我们迷途上的向导
Our guide in the wild.
黑暗里的领航灯
Our beacon in the darkness.
把她的背转过来 诺德
Turn her around, Nord.
她已经给我展示了路径
She has shown me the path!
在最神圣的时刻来临之际
And before the holy-most moment is upon us,
让我们为了伟大的老乔彻底疯狂一把
let's sacrifice one to old Saint Joe.
把我们这锈如废铁的破船开动起来 全速前进
And let's get this tub of shit up to speed.
Yep.
快划
Pull!
- 快划 - 快划
- Pull! - Pull!
- Pull. - Pull!
Ow.
- 我们要往哪个方向划? - 我他妈的也毫无头绪
- So which way we rowin'? - I don't have a goddamn clue.
别紧张
Don't worry.
等他们察觉被骗时起码也过了一个月了
They'll row for a month before they figure out I'm fakin' it.
但是为什么呢
But, um, wh-wh...
你想知道实情 不能告诉这些人
Oh, you want details. Well, I'm not tellin' these savages...
我们还没搞懂地图
that we haven't solved the map yet.
我向他们保证有结果 我会不择手段得到结果的
I promised them results, and I'll get 'em if I gotta cut 'em out of her goddamn back.
那是谁?那是谁?
Who is that? Who is that?
也许是个划桨的后备吧?
Maybe one of the spare rowers?
你怎么不去划桨呢?
Why aren't you rowin'?
- 是他 - 确实是他
- It's him. - It is him.
你们麻烦可大了
You guys are in so much trouble.
真的想不到 是那个鱼人
Well, I'll be damned. It's the gentleman guppy.
他好像洗不掉的狗屎
You know, he's like a turd that won't flush.
把那小姑娘给我
I want the girl.
知道吗?我以为你只是很蠢 老兄
You know, I thought you were stupid, friend.
不过我确实太低估你了
But I underestimated you.
你简直就是个低能儿
You're a total freakin' retard.
我只要那个女孩儿
I want the girl. That's all.
哦 在这荒凉残败的地球上 你凭什么认为你办得到?
Well, what on this screwed-up Earth makes you think you're gonna get her?
你知道这是什么吗?
You know what this is?
我丢下去你就毁了
I drop it, you burn.
- 大家都会毁了 - 等等 等等 先等等
- We all burn. - Now wait, wait, wait, wait.
都别冲动
Ahem. Let's not do anything rash here.
你确定她真的值得你这么做吗?
I mean, uh, are you sure she's worth all this?
她总是唠叨个没完没了 从不闭嘴
She never does stop talkin'. She never shuts up.
- 我清楚得很 - 那你是为什么?
- I noticed. - What is it then?
是为了地图?
Huh? It's the map.
她是我的朋友
She's my friend.
我真是感动得热泪直流
Golly gee. A single tear rolls down my cheek.
你居然要为了你的朋友准备慷慨就义
I mean, you're gonna die for your friend.
如果真有必要的话
If it comes to that.
只不是虚张声势罢了 我要杀了他
He's bluffing. I'll kill him.
他不是虚张声势 他从不会那么做
He's not bluffing. He never bluffs.
给我闭嘴
Shut up!
我打赌你绝不会扔的 我的朋友
I don't... l-l... I don't think you're gonna drop that torch, my friend.
- 为什么? - 因为你又不是疯子
- Why not? - Because you're not crazy.
不
No!
哦 真是感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
当心
Look out!
逮住他
Get him!
快点 可恶
Let's go, goddamn it!
别净站着 给我上
Don't just stand there! Kill somethin'!
这就是你伟大的幻景吗?
Was this your big vision?
我一直渴望能开开这玩意儿
Oh, yeah! I've always wanted to drive this monster.
是他 在那里
There he is! There he is!
在那里
That's him! There!
不 放手
No! Let go!
放手
Let go!
- 放手 放手 - 飞行员
- Let me go! Let go! - Pilot!
- 飞行员 - 放了我
- Pilot! - Let me go!
放了我!
Let go!
Let go-o-o-o!
你乖乖呆在水下就没事了
You should've stayed underwater.
你知道怎么驾驶飞机吗?幸好我懂 真庆幸对吧
Now you know how to fly an airplane? You're lucky I do.
别这样 给我听话点儿
Ow! Now you stop it! You behave yourself now!
它正在下沉
It's going down.
- 你能看见它在下沉 - 葛雷格 降到那艘船上方
- You can see it sinking. - Gregor, bring us right down on top of it.
- 快点 葛雷格 - 别担心
- Hurry, Gregor! - Don't worry.
快点
Hurry.
埃诺拉 快上来
Enola! Up here!
抓住绳子
Grab on!
他们俩都抓住了吗
Are they on yet?
- 怎么回事儿? - 不知道
- What is it? - I don't know!
不K
No!
抓到你了 我要好好地收拾你一顿
Gotcha! I'm gonna rip your cute little lungs out.
用力 差不多了
Pull! Almost.
不
No!
不 埃诺拉
No! Enola!
伟大的乔啊 这一杆进洞真漂亮啊
Saint Joe. Hole in one.
- 海伦 - 不 埃诺拉 - 海伦
- Helen! - No! Enola! - Helen!
嘿!嘿
Hey! Hey!
哦 不 快想办法啊 该怎么办
Ohh. Oh, no! Quick! What are we gonna do?
把这头绑紧
Tie this off.
- 快点 - 绑紧这头
- Hurry! - Tie it!
- 好了 - 噢
- Got it! - Ah!
快拉他们上来
Get 'em up now.
- 当然 北是南 - 什么
- Of course! North is south. - What?
- 南是北 - 我会游泳了
- South is north. - I was swimming.
- 我看到了 - 我的朋友们
- I saw. - My friends.
朋友们 快来看看
My friends, look.
只要我测出来太阳高度角
If I take a bearing from the sun
再颠倒一下埃诺拉背上的那些数据
and reverse the coordinates on Enola's back,
那么 陆地就应该是在那个方向
then Dryland is that way!
是淡水
It's fresh!
是淡水 全是淡水
All of this! It's fresh!
不!
No!
哇哦
Whoo! Whoo!
我发现了点东西
I found something!
也许我们应该让他们入土为安
Maybe we should put them under the dirt.
我想那是他们的风俗
I think it was their way.
他们一定早就知道自己将不久于人世了
They must have known they were dying.
我到家了
I'm home.
- 航海人在哪里? - 在外面
- Where's the Mariner? - He was outside.
等等 先等等!我想让你看看这个
Wait. Wait! I want to show you this.
这可能是你有生以来第一次只字不说吧?
First time in your life you got nothin' to say?
埃诺拉 我不得不马上离开
Enola, I have to go now.
但你曾为了我去而复返
But you came back for me.
我喜欢你
I like you.
你为什么要走?
Why are you leaving?
- 我不属于这里 我属于外面的世界 - 你属于这里
- I don't belong here. I belong out there. - You belong here.
呆在这儿让我觉得很别扭 因为一切都是静止的
It's too strange here. It doesn't move right.
海伦说那只不过是还没有适应脚踏实地的感觉罢了
Helen said that it's only land sickness.
我们都有这种感觉 但很快就能适应了
We're all feeling it. It'll go away soon.
不只是如此
It's more than that.